So there's going to be many times on this course that I take you through good principles for effective AI,
agentic engineering. And we're going to start now with the sort of basic five big ideas for successful
vibe coding. And it all comes under the heading, be the boss. The first one is one we've already
talked about, which is about spending time on your agents at MD. You want it to be concise,
and you want to cover importantly three different areas.
You want to spec what needs to be done very clearly.
You want to describe the style that it needs to be done in
and you need to be explaining what it means
to be successful so that it's absolutely clear
how to gauge success at the end of it.
That would be a good, concise, clear agent.md.
You need to start your project simple, straightforward, easy. And I'm not
just saying that in your agents.md, you begin the first section with something that's
easy. I'm saying your entire project, your first agents.md, should itself just be the
very basic MVP, but begin by building something basic in your whole agents.md. Go through
that entire iteration, including testing at each
point including sub steps make sure that it works and then decide to take it a
step more complex. If you try and start by boiling the ocean with a super
complicated application spelled out in your agents.md then you might go off
track off the rails it might not work and you'll just get stuck. So start simple.
And obviously that goes along with that is to then work incrementally,
constantly testing, constantly validating the success criteria at each step. If you're working in
this very regimented way, this disciplined way, then you can guarantee at each point that you've
reached that milestone successfully, and you can always go back if you haven't. And then, you know, these all sort of belong together, but don't get lazy,
avoid the trap, especially when you've had some early success with vibe coding. It's gone off
and built you a first person shooter. It's gone off and built you a camban and you're thinking,
oh, wow, this just works. I'll just yolo. I'll just set it off. I'll come back later.
And then I'll just keep pushing ahead. And it's so tempting. It is so easy to get lazy to start to take it for granted and
start to just sort of trust it. It's like, ah, that's going to be working. It's, it looks great.
If you do that, your, your defenses come down, you let your guard down and you go several steps
forwards. And only then you realize that, that several steps ago, it made some terrible assumption
that is complete nonsense. And as a result, you've just wasted lots of time.
So, you know, the onus is on you to be challenging at each step.
If there's, if you're debugging something and it declares it's found the problem and
fixed it and here's why with lots of confident bold text, still challenge.
Come in, demand the evidence.
Have you found the root cause?
Have you fixed it?
Are you sure?
Give me the evidence, demonstrate it,
show me the test results, and then move on.
But don't allow your guard to come down.
Don't just go with it, even when you have some successes.
One thing's for sure, you're gonna have moments
when you will be blown away by how well it goes,
how much code is built,
how something like the camper
and disappears that is really cool.
It's gonna be amazing.
But there will also be times when it's a fiasco.
There will be chaos. There will be times when it makes a mistake and then it makes
the same mistake again and you put it in agents.md and you say never, ever make this
mistake and it makes it again. And you say write a performance report that says I will
never make this mistake again and read that performance report every single time.
And it still moves on the stage.
When these things happen, it can be so frustrating.
I've had moments when I have been just so angry.
And what you have to keep telling yourself
and what you gradually learn is that
that is part of the process.
You're hitting up against limitations
of the model that you're working with.
And you need to find how to work around that,
you need to detect it, manage it, handle it and do so with style. This is the frustration,
the walls that you can hit against, that is part of the process. These models give you an enormous
leg up in some ways, but they also have their downsides and managing the downsides is the key
path to success. Now, you might be thinking to yourself, these five principles to set me up for success,
they seem to fly in the face of Yolo.
It's very much about not just,
"Hey, I'm gonna kick it off.
"I'm gonna let it have permission.
"Do whatever you want.
"I'm coming back in an hour or in a day."
That seems a bit different.
And you're right.
And you know, you could probably tell,
"I'm not a huge fan of Yolo.
"There are situations as we'll discuss
"when it makes sense to do it,
but always with a skeptical eye,
always be the boss as much as you can.
Even if you YOLO, come back and check everything carefully.
People talk about the trust but verify mindset
that I think I mentioned before.
You need to trust it to a certain extent
and then verify very carefully indeed.
That is certainly my recipe for success.
Even with the really strong models,
you need to be the boss.
That's the path to success.
And on that note, I got some words of wisdom
for whether you're from a junior background
or from a senior engineer background.
I just have some things to say.
If you're from coming into this as like new to programming
or a junior engineer on that end of the continuum,
then first up, you need to use this as an opportunity
to be learning.
You want to take that journey yourself
so that you can become a senior engineer in the future.
And so, don't allow yourself to lose sight
of the learning opportunity here.
Take this as a way to challenge and ask questions
of the LLM in order that you can understand
what's happening so that you're learning it too.
So you're making that journey towards being a senior engineer.
Otherwise it would be so easy just to sort of
not ever acquire that skillset and just let the model do,
do the work, which will only lead to frustration later.
And similarly, you need to be skeptical.
The mental model to have is that you've got this,
this assistant that's super eager
and that will go and hunt on the internet and research things and do
stuff. But sometimes it's misguided and sometimes it's overconfident and makes a
mistake or it uses band aids instead of doing a proper solution. It guesses a lot all those
kinds of problems that we've talked about in the past and you have to be wise to that.
So come at it with a healthy skepticism, ask the right questions,
always double check, even if it seems confident,
always have that healthy skepticism in mind
and things will go much better.
And for senior engineers, to be honest,
this tooling is best suited for you.
It's harder for the junior engineers.
Sorry, junior engineers.
It's harder because you just sort of can feel bamboozled by this thing sometimes.
And you can't tell if it's making it up or not.
But as a senior engineer, you can tell.
And so you're actually in a really good position to use it.
The point I want to make to you is you need to keep in mind that this is a tool that allows
you to build more when used correctly.
I don't like to get caught up in the hype.
I don't know that it's a 10x, but it's certainly something that allows you to do more
and build more.
And so my, my, my ask, my appeal is that you keep enjoying what you do.
What excites most of us engineers is the fact of building.
And sure, a lot of what gives me satisfaction is hammering out code and seeing it run.
And so there's a sense when I work with L.A.
Lens that some of that joy is being taken away from me.
But really it's a trade.
It's true that joy is being taken away of writing a line of code.
But instead of that, I have this other joy that I
am able to build entire systems like frontend
that I'm so terrible at.
Now I can just have a frontend built just like that.
I can have terraformed scripts written and things deployed,
DevOps stuff that I'm on.
And that can be done really, really fast with LLMs.
And so it's given me all these extra powers
I didn't have before, and that allows me to build faster,
and building faster is fun.
So I guess my ask is to try and keep in mind
that whilst it's taken something's away,
it's given a lot more back.
And in summary, I have a balanced view
when it comes to the productivity improvement that
coding agents bring us.
I do see that there are situations when it's literally a 10x change in productivity,
like the Building a Camban view in the next AS app.
That would take me days, maybe even a week, whereas it was just a matter of minutes.
So there are clearly situations where it is a game changer.
But there are situations where that's definitely not the case. There are times when it's just an incremental
productivity improvement, particularly with larger projects, legacy projects,
with complex back-end changes. And there are situations where it actually
subtracts value. I have had real-world situations where I've been trying to build
like a streamable HTTP/MCP server, something that's relatively new and wasn't part of its training data and
Claude was messing it up for me again and again and it took me longer than it would have taken if
I just wrote it myself. So it's a mixed bag and recognizing that it's a mixed bag is a big part of
the challenge. You could come into this, you could have a lot of success, you could think to
yourself, wow, I can change
my estimates to attend to what they were. And then you hit a stumbling block and the
next thing you know, everything has been pushed out. So keep a healthy understanding
of both the positives and the downsides of working with coding agents.
And in aggregate, the main thing to take away is that I would say it's always a positive,
it's always value add now. Using the top coding agents, always speeds things up.
How much it speeds things up depends hugely
on the kind of task, on the kinds of skills
that you have, on the size of the project,
and many other factors.
But you quickly get to understand
what kind of boost you're going to get
once you're a little bit into that project.
Generally speaking, if you're dealing with a small MVP
of a green field project, you're going to get
a very significant multiplier of your productivity.
In most other cases, you're talking about a speed improvement, you're talking about
assistance, but not the kind of 10X numbers that you sometimes see in all of the hype.